My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقلي عقل مُتحرٍّ عظيم
Today's case is a two-part story aboard a luxury liner!
قضيّة اليوم من جزأين على متن سفينة !سياحية فاخرة
Think you can tell who did it just from Part 1?
أيمكنكم معرفة المجرم من الجزء الأوّل يا ترى؟
There's always only one truth!
!الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
The Luxury Liner Murders, Part 1.
سلسلة جرائم قتل السفينة السياحية الفاخرة (الجزء الأوّل)
What a beautiful view!
!يا للمنظر البديع
We sure were lucky! I was worried for a while there!
حصل وأن شعرتُ بالقلق للحظات، لكن حالفنا الحظّ
Yeah!
أجل
so we got to ride on this big one instead!
وصعدنا على هذه السفينة الكبيرة مكانها
It was a good thing this ship just happened to stop at the island.
من الحسن أن صادفَ وتوقّفتْ هذه السفينة عند الجزيرة
We would've been stranded out there for 3 days if it hadn't.
كنّا لنُعزل في ذاك المكان النائي لثلاثة أيام
But I wonder what kind of people would reserve a ship like this...
لكن أيّ نوع من الأشخاص قد يحجزون سفينةً كهذه؟
Is something the matter?
أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
No, it's nothing...
لا، لا شيء
I was just thinking about my parents who died in an accident last year...
كنتُ أفكر بوالديّ اللذين ماتا في حادث العام الفائت
I wish they could've seen me all dressed up today...
ليتهما يرياني بزينتي اليوم
All dressed up?
بزينتك؟
Is something wrong, Natsue?
أهناك خطبٌ ما يا ناتسوي؟
Takeshi-san!
!تاكيشي-سان
The two of us were married today!
!تزوّجنا اليوم في الواقع
Married?!
تزوّجتما؟
We had our ceremony this morning on Hatamoto Island,
أقمنا الحفل في جزيرة هاتاموتو هذا الصباح
Shoichi's 2nd daughter Hatamoto Natsue (22) Natsue's Husband Hatamoto Takeshi (24)
ابنة شويتشي الثانية (هاتاموتو ناتسوي (22
the same island you were on!
نفس الجزيرة التي كنتم عليها
Congratulations!
!مُبارك
But why did you have it on the island?
لكن لمَ أقمتماه على تلك الجزيرة بالذات؟
The majority of the island belongs to the Hatamoto family.
تخصّ معظم الجزيرة عائلة هاتاموتو
We honor generations of our ancestors there.
نقدّم الاحترام لأجيال من أسلافنا هناك
It's a Hatamoto family tradition to hold wedding ceremonies on the island.
من تقاليد عائلة هاتاموتو إقامة حفلات الزواج على الجزيرة
You fool!
!أحمق
We reserved this boat for ourselves, so what are strangers doing on it?!
حجزنا هذه السفينة بأكملها، فلمَ يوجد !غرباء على متنها؟
I'm sorry!
!آ-آسف
They appeared to be stranded, so...
...بدوا أنّهم في مأزق فـ
How dare you go over my head!
تفعل دون استشارتي
You must think pretty highly of yourself
أصبحتَ رفيع المقام إن كنت تأخذ
if you're making decisions without approval.
قرارات دون الرجوع لي
No, of course I don't!
!كلا، أبداً
Don't worry about it.
لا تقلقي حيال ذلك
He's been in a bad mood since the ceremony today.
كان جدّي في مزاج سيّئ مُذ الحفل اليوم
Yes, after he ate my food...
صحيح، بعدما أكل طعامي
Uncle Joji!
!عمّي جوجي
I knew he hated Western-style food, but I had no idea he'd get that angry.
،كنتُ أعرف أنّه يكره الطعام الغربي لكن لم أعلم أنّه سيغضب لهذا الحد
You call this food?!
!تعتبر هذا طعاماً؟
It seems my skills still aren't up to par.
يبدو أنّ مهاراتي لا تزال ناقصة
Second son of the Hatamoto family Hatamoto Joji (41)
ابن عائلة هاتاموتو الثاني (هاتاموتو جوجي (41
Don't say that!
ليس صحيحاً
It was really delicious!
!كان لذيذاً جداً
Say, lady-killer... What's with the flower?
أخبرني يا خاطف القلوب، ما حكاية هذه الزهرة؟
Oh, Natsue put it there on the way back from the ceremony.
وضعتها ناتسوي عليّ في عودتنا من الحفل
It's always been my dream since I was a little girl
كان حُلمي منذ صغري
to give my beloved this flower that only grows on that island.
أن أعطي هذه الزهرة التي تنمو على تلك الجزيرة فقط لأعزّ الناس عليّ
Too bad it wasn't me...
...راحت عليّ
Kitaro's only son Hatamoto Ichiro (21)
ابن كيتارو الوحيد (هاتاموتو إيتشيرو (21
Like father, like son!
ذاك الابن من ذاك الأب
How long are you going to let him pretend to be an artist?!
إلى متى ستدعه يواصل التّظاهر أنّه رسّام؟
You're his father, talk some sense into him!
!أنتَ أبوه فاعقله
Tell him to give up his hopeless dream!
!أخبره أن ييأس من حلمه المستحيل
Yes!
حاضر
Takeshi-kun!
!تاكيشي-كن
Yes?
أ-أجل
I need a word with you! Come to my room later!
أريد مكالمتك، تعال إلى غرفتي لاحقاً
Yes, sir...
حـ-حاضر
Just have patience, dear.
تحلّ بالصبر الآن يا عزيزي
He isn't long for this world-- he'll be gone soon enough.
لم يبق لأبي وقتٌ طويل، ساعة عمره تنفد
Eldest Hatamoto daughter, Kitaro's wife, Hatamoto Mariko (43)
ابنة هاتاموتو البكر وزوجة كيتارو (هاتاموتو ماريكو (43
And when he is, nearly all of the Hatamoto fortune will be yours!
وعندها ستصبح مجموعة هاتاموتو وثروتها !كلّها من نصيبك تقريباً
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
لا أظنّ ذلك يا عمّة
What's that supposed to mean?!
!ما قصدك؟
Akie-san! Do you know something I don't?!
!أكي-سان! أتعرفين شيئاً أجهله؟
Shoichi's daughter & Natsue's sister Hatamoto Akie (26)
ابنة شويتشي وأخت ناتسوي (هاتاموتو أكي (26
Don't be too shocked when you hear.
لا تسقطي من الصدمة بعدما تسمعين
Impossible! That can't be true!
!مـ-محال! لا يمكن ذلك
It sounds like Grandfather's going to make the announcement
يبدو أنّ جدّي سيعلن الأمر
when we get back to Tokyo.
بعدما نرجع لطوكيو
Gimme a break.
لا تمازحني
Akie's husband Hatamoto Tatsuo (26)
زوج أكي (هاتاموتو تاتسو (26
NDoes he even know we're up to our necks in debt over here?!
أيعرف أنّنا غارقون في الديون؟
We have 24 hours until the ship arrives in Tokyo.
أمامنا 24 ساعة حتى تصل السفينة طوكيو
We simply have to do something before then...
علينا فعل شيءٍ قبل ذاك
It's me, Takeshi.
أنا تاكيشي
Enter.
ادخل
Sorry to disturb you.
أعتذر على التطفل
That was an exceptional speech you gave at the wedding.
كانت كلمتك محترمةً في الزفاف
Just what I would expect of the man whom Natsue chose.
لا عجب من الرجل الذي اختارته ناتسوي
Thank you...
شكراً جزيلاً
Scratching your cheeks when you're embarrassed...
...حكّك لخدّك عند الإحراج
You're just like him.
أنتَ مثله
Just like your father, Zaiki Isao!
!أقصد أباك، زايكي إيساو
Falsify your family registry all you want, you still cannot fool me!
،يمكنك تزييف سجلاتك العائلية !لكنك لن تخدعني
I've known all this time that you joined the company
أعرف أنّك دخلت شركتي وتقرّبت من ناتسوي
and got close to Natsue just to avenge your father!
!كي تأخذ بانتقام والدك
What is it you're after?
ما الذي تسعى وراءه؟
Money?
المال؟
Or my life, perhaps?
أم حياتي ربما؟
What's the matter? Why won't you speak?!
!ما الخطب؟ لمَ لا تنطق؟
Answer me!
!أجب
These are the main members of the Hatamoto family.
هذه شجرة عائلة هاتاموتو الرئيسية
So all of these people went to your wedding?
حضر كلّ هؤلاء زفافك إذاً؟
Yes! All nine of them,
أجل، التسعة منهم باستثناء والديّ المتوفيّين
excluding my late parents Shoichi and Miyuki.
وشويتشي وميوكي
Say, Takeshi-san is rather late...
...لكن، تأخّر تاكيشي-سان بالفعل
Yes. He still hasn't come back from Grandfather's room...
أجل، لم يعد مذ ذهب لغرفة جدّي
I wonder what happened.
ماذا حصل يا ترى؟
Maybe they're discussing some under-the-table business!
لعلّهما يناقشان أعمال لا شرعية
Akie!
أختي
You're late.
تأخّرت
Sorry.
آسف
Dad not here yet?
لم يأت أبي بعد؟
Hatamoto family butler Suzuki Kenji (64)
كلا، لكني أعتقد أنّه سيأتي قريباً
No, though I am certain he will be here shortly.
كبير خدم عائلة هاتاموتو (سوزوكي كينجي (64
You're late, Ichiro-san!
تأخّرت يا إيتشيرو-سان
Did you make sure to wash your hands?!
هل غسلت يديك كما يجب؟
Yes...
أجل
Say! Do you have a boyfriend, Ran-san?
أخبريني يا ران-سان، ألديك حبيب وما شابه؟
Of course not, she's still a kid...
بالطبع لا، لا تزال طفلة
How rude!
هذه فظاظة
I'll have you know there is someone I like!
حتّى أنا لديّ شخص أحبه
Right, Conan-kun?
صحيح يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah...
...أ-أجل
What's he like?
كيف هو؟
Well, he's really smart, good at soccer, dependable, and cool!
حسناً، إنّه لامع الذكاء وبارع في كرة القدم !وأهلٌ للمسؤولية وقت الحاجة، إنّه رائعٌ جداً
What are you acting so embarrassed about?
لمَ تحمّر أنت خجلاً؟
And he's an even better detective than my dad!
!وهو متحرٍّ أفضل حتّى من أبي
You mean your father's a--
...تقصدين أنّ أباكِ
Oh? I didn't tell you?
ماذا؟ لم أخبركم؟
My dad's a detective!
أنّ أبي مُتحرٍّ؟
Is something the matter?
أ-أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
Keep it a secret from my grandfather! He hates detectives!
اكتموا الأمر عن جدّي، فهو يكره المتحرّيين
He says that people who pry into others' affairs are despicable!
يقول أنّ الناس الذين يدسّون أنوفهم في أمور الناس بغيضو الطبع
He's right, at least in old man Kogoro's case.
إنّه صادق في حالة العمّ كوغورو على الأقل
Sir? Your seat is ready, sir...
سيّدي، مقعدك بانتظارك
A flower?
زهرة؟
Takeshi-san! You're really late!
!تاكيشي-سان! تأخّرت كثيراً
Sorry, I was thinking about some things in my room.
آسف، كنتُ غارقاً في التفكير في غرفتي
Are you alright? You look pale.
أأنت بخير؟ تبدو شاحباً
Oh? What happened to your flower?
ماذا؟ أين الزهرة التي أعطيتك؟
That's strange. Where could I have lost it?
غريب، أين فقدتها؟
Sorry to disturb you, sir.
أعتذر على مضايقتك سيّدي
Everyone is waiting for you--
...الجميع بانتظار
Whose voice was that?!
!ما كان ذاك الصوت؟
The butler's!
!الخادم سوزوكي
It came from Dad's room!
!أتى من غرفة أبي
What happened, Suzuki-san?!
!ما الخطب يا سوزوكي-سان؟
It's too late. He's dead.
فات الأوان، فارق الحياة
No!
لا يمكن
Grandfather!
!جدّي
Stop!
!توقفي
Everyone stay out!
!لا يدخل أحد
Nobody's to enter this room until I say it's okay!
لا يمكن لأحد دخول هذه الغرفة حتى أسمح
It would seem that 40 or 50 minutes have passed since Gozo's death.
يبدو أنّ 40 أو 50 دقيقة مضت منذ موت غوزو
You were the one who found him, Suzuki-san?
كنتَ من وجده، صحيح يا سوزوكي-سان؟
Yes.
أجل
Where were you 40 to 50 minutes ago, around 8:00 PM?
،أين كنت قبل 40 إلى 50 دقيقة أي عند قرابة الثامنة؟
I was getting things ready for dinner at 8:00,
كنتُ أجهّز للعشاء عند الثامنة
so I was in the dining room the entire time.
فكنتُ في غرفة الطعام طوال الوقت
I did see Suzuki-san working in a hurry around the tables!
رأينا سوزوكي-سان في عمله متعجلاً بين الطاولات بالفعل
The door to this room was locked when you found the body, correct?
كان باب هذه الغرفة مقفل عندما وجدث الجثة، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
What ways are there to lock the door?
وأيّ طرق لقفل الباب؟
It can be locked from the inside,
،يمكن قفله من الداخل
but you need this key to lock it from the outside.
لكن تحتاج لهذا المفتاح لقفله من الخارج
And this window doesn't open, so it's impossible to sneak into the room.
والنافذة هنا لا تُفتح، فيستحيل التسلل لها من الخارج
In other words, this room was impregnable!
مما يعني أنّها كانت غرفةً مغلقة تماماً
Impregnable?!
غرفة مغلقة؟
You're saying that my grandfather committed suicide?!
أتقصد أنّ جدّي قد انتحر؟
But it's strange.
لكن هذا غريب
If it was a suicide, then there's something important missing here.
لو كان انتحاراً فهناك شيء مفقود
The weapon.
السلاح
He died of blood loss after being stabbed in the abdomen.
مات من النزيف بعدما طُعن في المعدة
But the knife used to do it is nowhere to be found.
لكن لا أثر للسكّين التي اُستعملت
Are you sure it wasn't a dagger made of ice or anything?
لعلّه كان خنجراً من جليد وما شابه
Mystery novels are full of things that melt away and stuff.
فروايات التحرّي مليئة بالأشياء التي تذوب ويزول أثرها
Would someone seriously commit suicide with something like that?
هل سيفكّر شخص ينتحر بشيءٍ كهذا؟
I bet this is more of his harassment.
إنها مضايقة من جدّي حتماً
He wanted to torment us by making every Hatamoto here seem suspect!
أراد أن يعاني جميع أفراد هاتاموتو هنا برميهم في دائرة الشبهة
He hated everyone in the family, after all.
فقد كان يكرههم جميعاً
Everyone except Natsue-san, that is.
صحيح، باستثناء ناتسوي
Akie!
!أ-أختي
I wouldn't put it past the old man...
...لا أستبعد الفعلة عنه
Then it's decided! It was a suicide!
!كان انتحاراً إذاً! حُسِم الأمر
This was a murder.
هذه جريمة قتل
What?!
!ماذا؟
And an extremely simple one, at that.
وواحدة بغاية البساطة
You, again?!
!أنت مجدداً؟
Here, take a close look at the doorframe!
هنا، أمعن النظر لإطار المدخل
See the blood?
أترى الدم؟
If the door was closed when he committed suicide,
لو كان الباب مغلقاً عندما أقدم على الانتحار
none of his blood could have landed there.
ما كنّا لنجد دماً هنا، صحيح؟
So it's more natural to think that he was stabbed while the door was open.
إذا فكّرنا منطقيّاً فقد طُعِن بينما الباب مفتوح
That's it! Somebody stabbed Gozo the instant he left the room!
!صحيح! طعن أحدهم غوزو لحظة مغادرته الغرفة
Then who locked the door?
من أقفل الغرفة إذاً؟
No clue...
من يا ترى؟
Hey, you sure you're a detective?
أتعرف عملك حقاً؟
That's it! It was Mr. Gozo himself who locked the door!
!فهمت! كان غوزو نفسه من أقفل الباب
Someone stabbed him outside the room and then kept coming for him,
طعنه أحدهم خارج الغرفة ثمّ واصل هجومه
so he locked himself inside to escape his attacker!
ففرّ غوزو للغرفة وأقفل الباب
But then he ran out of strength and died!
لكن خارتْ قِواه ومات
I see. That would make the most sense.
فهمت، هذا منطقيّ
You're such a great detective!
!كما يُتوقع منك يا عمّي، استنتاج عظيم
Wait a minute! That means everyone had an opportunity to kill him!
لحظة، هذا يعني كان للجميع فرصة لقتله
The murder took place at approximately 8:00.
وقعت الجريمة قرابة الثامنة
Ran, Conan, Natsue-san, and I were at our table since 7:30,
كنتُ وران وكونان وناتسوي-سان عند طاولتنا منذ السابعة والنصف
so none of us could have done it!
فيستحيل أن يكون أحدنا
The same can be said for Suzuki-san, who was near our table at the time.
ينطبق الأمر على سوزوكي-سان الذي كان قرب طاولتنا
In other words, since the killer wasn't in the dining room at the time...
بعبارة أخرى، بما أن القاتل لم يكن ...في غرفة الطعام آنذاك
...it was one of you seven!
!كان أحدكم أنتم السبعة
Suzuki-san.
سوزوكي-سان
When you entered the room, did you notice anything out of the ordinary?
هل لاحظت شيئاً غريباً عند دخولك الغرفة؟
No, nothing in particular...
كلا، لا شيء تحديداً
Oh, now that you mention it, I found this flower in front of the door...
تذكرت، وجدتُ هذه الزهرة أمام الباب
Flower?
زهرة؟
That's the flower I put on Takeshi-san's jacket!
إ-إنّها الزهرة التي علّقتها على معطف تاكيشي-سان
Come to think of it, you were really late coming to the dining room.
صحيح، تأخّرت في القدوم لغرفة الطعام
No, I was just thinking about things in my room...
بربك، كنتُ جالساً أفكر في غرفتي فقط
Don't try to deny it, Takeshi-san.
لا تحاول الإنكار يا تاكيشي-سان
I happened to hear you and Father shouting in his room!
سمعتُ الصراخ بينك وأبي عندما كنتُ أمرّ أمام الغرفة
I thought I was going to faint
ظننتُ أنّي سأسقط من الدهشة
when I heard that you're actually the son of Zaiki Isao!
!عندما سمعتُ أنّك ابن زايكي إيساو
Who's Zaiki Isao?
من زايكي إيساو ذاك؟
He committed suicide when Gozo took over his company 10 years ago.
شخص أقدم على الانتحار عندما استحوذ غوزو على شركته قبل 10 أعوام
One year later, his wife died of an illness,
ولحقت زوجته به بعد عام من مرض
and their only son was apparently placed in an institution.
فُوضع ابنهما الوحيد في مركز رعاية ما
To think that that was Takeshi-kun!
من كان ليتصور أنّه تاكيشي-كن
Is it true, Takeshi-san?!
أهذا صحيح يا تاكيشي-سان؟
Takeshi-san!
!تاكيشي-سان
Yeah. I'm Zaiki Takeshi, son of Zaiki Isao!
!أجل، أنا ابن زايكي إيساو، زايكي تاكيشي
But I...!
...لـ-لكني
...Got close to Natsue-san so you could avenge your father?
تقرّبت من ناتسوي-سان كي تأخذ بثأر أبيك؟
You decided to become a member of the Hatamoto family
قرّرت دخول عائلة هاتاموتو
and wait for the chance to kill Gozo.
وانتظار فرصة قتل غوزو
And then tonight, you did just that!
!وذلك ما ارتكبته الليلة
No! I didn't kill him!
!كلا! لم أقتله
Natsue! Wait!
!ناتسوي! انتظري
I had you pegged as a pretty staunch fellow,
،ظننتُ أنّك شاب قويم
but it looks like I was wrong.
لكن يبدو أنّي أخطأت
Joji-san!
جوجي-سان
You gotta be an idiot to drop your flower at the crime scene!
يا لحماقتك لإسقاطك الزهرة عند موقع الجريمة
I didn't, I lost my flower somewhere!
!لم أفعل، فقدتها في مكانٍ ما
There are wiped blood stains on the outside carpet...
توجد آثار دم ممحوّة على السجاد خارجاً
Say, was that flower really here on the floor?
أكانت الزهرة ساقطة هنا حقاً؟
Yes, that's right, little boy.
أجل يا بنيّ
What's this?
ما هذا؟
A bread crumb!
!كسرة خبز
A bread crumb lying in a pool of blood?
كسرة خبز في بركة الدماء؟
What's it mean?!
ما معنى هذا؟
Say, Mr. Butler.
أخبرني سيّدي
Was there bread during the wedding banquet this afternoon?
أكان هناك خبزٌ في مأدبة الزفاف هذه الظهيرة؟
But of course--it was an extravagant French meal.
بالطبع، فقد كان طعاماً فرنسياً فاخراً
Joji-sama made it all himself. He runs his own French restaurant.
طهاه جوجي-ساما الذي يدير مطعماً فرنسياً
Did everyone eat it?
هل أكله الجميع؟
Yes. Everyone but Gozo-sama.
أجل، باستثناء غوزو-ساما
He loathed Western-style food.
فقد كان يكره الطعام الغربي
He said that just looking at bread would make him nauseous.
قال أنّ مجرد النظر للخبز يشعره بالغثيان
If Joji-san's a chef, he has kitchen knives of his own, right?
لو كان جوجي-سان طاهياً، فلديه مجموعة سكاكينه المطبخية الخاصة، صحيح؟
Naturally. Chefs like him always own their own set.
بالطبع، فللطهاة مثله مجموعاتهم دوماً
Come now, children shouldn't pry into other people's business.
اسمع، لا يصحّ بالأطفال التطفل على شؤون الآخرين
Get in there!
ادخل
Cool off in this storeroom for a while.
هدّئ أعصابك في المخزن لفترة
Open up! Please!
!افتح! أرجوك! لم أكن القاتل
Don't be stupid, you murderer!
لا تعبث معي يا مجرم
We're giving you to the police the minute we arrive in Tokyo tomorrow!
سنسلمك للشرطة لحظة وصولنا لطوكيو غداً
Better get ready!
حضّر نفسك
His motive and all the evidence is more than enough, right, Detective?
الدافع والدليل كافيان، صحيح حضرة المتحرّي؟
He had more than enough motive.
لديه دافعٌ كافٍ
And if his fingerprints are found on the murder weapon, it's in the bag.
وستكتمل القضية إن وجدنا بصماته على سلاح الجريمة
Here you are.
تفضّلي
Thank you!
شكراً لك
Here you go, little boy.
هاك يا فتى
You sure are lucky, Mariko.
يا لحظّك يا عمّة ماريكو
Now that Takeshi-san has killed the old man,
،بعد أن قتل تاكيشي-سان جدّي
he'll never make that stupid announcement about his inheritance!
لن يقوم بذاك الإعلان الساذج عن إرثه
That's true.
معكِ حق
Now the Hatamoto Group will belong to you,
أصبحت مجموعة هاتاموتو لك الآن
the husband of his eldest daughter!
يا زوج الابنة البكر
And you can draw as much as you want,
ويمكنك الرسم كما تحبّ يا إيتشيرو-سان
now that your grandfather's dead, Ichiro-san!
!بعد وفاة جدّك
And eventually, you too will become the Hatamoto Group's--
...وبنهاية المطاف، ستصبح أنت رئيس مجموعة هاتاموتو
I don't really want that...
...لا-لا أنوي ذلك حقاً
Hey, you ain't thinkin' of monopolizing the guy's inheritance, are ya?
لا تخططين للاستحواذ على إرث العجوز وحدك، صحيح؟
Don't worry! All you grandchildren will get--
...لا تقلق، ستحصلون الأحفاد جميعاً
Could you not talk about money on the night of our father's death?
هلا توقفتِ عن الحديث حول المال يا أختي في ليلة وفاة أبي؟
Who're you to talk? You left the family to go be a chef!
لا حقّ لك بالكلام بعدما تركت العائلة لتصبح طاهياً
I know that Father flat out refused you
أنا أعرف
when you asked to borrow money for your restaurant!
!لأجل مطعمك
You wanted his money too! So be grateful!
أردت حصّةً من ماله أيضاً، فلتُسرّ
Um...
المعذرة
I'm extremely sorry to say this,
...يؤسفني قول هذا
but your father wrote up a will
لكن كتب أبوك وصيّةً
just in case something was to happen to him...
في حال حصل مكروهٌ له
What?!
!ماذا؟
I believe it will be read at the main office in the next few days.
أظن أنّها ستُقرأ في المكتب الرئيسي بعد بضعة أيام
Does that mean--?
...أ-أيعني هذا
All of his fortune goes to--
...كلّ ثروته ستكون من نصيب
Natsue?!
!ناتسوي؟
Yes.
أجل
And leadership of the Hatamoto Group is to be given to the man
ورئاسة مجموعة هاتاموتو ستُعطى للرجل للذي اختارته
that Natsue-san chose.
ناتسوي-ساما
This can't be!
!لا يُعقل
What? Then what the hell did I marry Akie for?!
!يا للهول! ما فائدة زواجي من أكي إذاً؟
Don't tell me you only married me to get my dad's money!
أتقصد أنّك تزوجتني لمال جدّي من البداية؟
That's right! Why else would I live with a tight-fisted bitch like you?!
أجل، صحيح! وإلّا لمَ أريد الارتباط !بشحيحةٍ بائسة مثلك؟
Who're you to talk?! You're just a worthless musician!
!ماذا؟! تقول هذا وأنت مجرد موسيقيّ عديم الموهبة
Go and get a real job!
!اعمل كبقية الناس
Natsue-san?
ناتسوي-سان؟
What are you doing out here?
ماذا تفعلين هنا؟
Nothing, just thinking.
لا شيء، أفكّر قليلاً فقط
About Takeshi-san?
في تاكيشي-سان؟
I trusted him...
...وثقتُ به، كنت مؤمنة
But he only married me so he could kill my grandfather!
!لكنّه تزوجني كي يقتل جدّي فقط
I'll never trust anyone again!
!لن أثق بأحد مُجدداً
I trust him.
أنا أثق به
My gut feeling tells me that he's not a bad person.
يخبرني حدسي بشكلٍ ما أنّه ليس شخصاً سيّئاً
He's the one you chose, after all.
فهو من اخترتِه، صحيح؟
He couldn't possibly be a bad person!
يستحيل أن يكون رجلاً سيّئاً
Ran-san...
...ران-سان
Hey, what are you--
...ماذا
Hey, did you hear anything strange just now?
ألم تسمعا صوتاً غريباً؟
Did you hear anything, Natsue-san?
أسمعتِ شيئاً يا ناتسوي-سان؟
No...
لا، لا شيء
No, I did hear something!
كلا، سمعتُ بالفعل
The sound of something falling into the water
صوت شيءٍ يسقط في الماء
and then a weird thud from the deck below!
ثمّ ارتطام غريب من السطح السفلي
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Wait, Conan-kun! What's going on?!
!انتظر يا كونان-كن! ماذا يجري؟
What's gotten into you two--?
...ما خطبكما
The cause of death was most likely brain damage
سبب الموت كان إصابة دماغية غالباً
caused by a blow to the head.
جرّاء ضربة للرأس
Judging from the wound,
،بناءً على الجرح
the murder weapon was a steel pipe or something similar.
كان سلاح الجريمة أنبوباً حديدياً وما شابه
Who would do something this terrible?!
من قد يفعل شيئاً فظيعاً كهذا؟
Don't tell me Takeshi's struck again!
...أيمكن أنّ تاكيشي مُجدداً
Impossible. He was locked in.
مستحيل، الباب مقفل
Hey! Conan!
!انتظر، كونان
The door's unlocked!
!القفل مفتوح
Out of the way!
ابتعد
He's gone!
!ليس موجوداً
He wasn't in the storeroom?!
!لم يكن في المخزن؟
We most certainly locked him inside, but he's nowhere to be found.
أقفلنا عليه حتماً، لكن لم نجده بأيّ مكان
So Takeshi was the one who killed Father and Tatsuo-san!
!كان تاكيشي من قتل أبي وتاتسو-سان إذاً
The thud that Conan heard
صوت الارتطام الذي سمعه كونان
was probably the sound of the killer hitting Tatsuo-san.
كان صوت ضربة القاتل لتاتسو-سان غالباً
The splash he heard
وصوت الارتطام بالماء
was either the sound of the murder weapon being thrown overboard, or...
كان صوت رمي القاتل للسلاح ...الذي استعمله، أو
...the sound of the killer jumping into the water
صوت قفزه في المحيط
after running out of places to hide!
بعدما لم يعد له مفرّ
Takeshi-san...
تاكيشي-سان
At any rate, there's still a high possibility
بأيّ حال، لا يزال هناك احتمال كبير
that there's a killer aboard this ship.
بوجود القاتل على متن السفينة
Let's all withdraw to the dining room for now.
لنتراجع جميعاً لغرفة الطعام حالياً
Are you saying he could be trying to kill me?!
!أتقصد أنّه قد يحاول قتلي؟
Have you forgotten?!
أنسيتِ؟
His motive for murder was to exact revenge on Hatamoto Gozo,
كان دافعه للجريمة الأخذ بثأر أبيه من هاتاموتو غوزو
who drove his father to suicide 10 years ago!
الذي دفعه للانتحار قبل 10 أعوام
But for all we know...
...لا نستطيع استبعاد
...he could be trying to kill everyone in the Hatamoto family!
!أنه قد يحاول إبادة كلّ عائلة هاتاموتو
I know that you have another man!
!أعرف أنّ هناك رجالاً آخرين في حياتك
You're the one who wants the inheritance the most!
!أنتِ أكثر من أراد إرثه
Even Ichiro was mad at him
حتى إيتشيرو اعتراه الغضب
for tearing up his prize-winning drawing!
!بعدما مزّق جدّي رسمته المتوّجة بجائزة
Ichiro!
!إيتشيرو
My leg!
!ساقي
This is my knife...
...هذه سكّيني
All of these mysteries are connected by one thread!
كلّ هذه الألغاز مربوطة بخيط
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Luxury Liner Murders, Part 2.
سلسلة جرائم قتل السفينة السياحية الفاخرة الجزء الثاني
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Sketch book.
دفتر رسم